<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="configuration.xsl"?>

<configuration>

    <tagme_info>
        <description>
            The tagme_info tag is used for setting all configuration parameter necessary to interact with the tagme
            server.
        </description>
        <url>
            <description>
                The TagME URL related to annotation operation
            </description>
            <value>
                https://tagme.d4science.org/tagme/tag
            </value>
        </url>
        <url_rel>
            <description>
                The TagME URL related to relatedness computation
            </description>
            <value>
                https://tagme.d4science.org/tagme/rel
            </value>
        </url_rel>
        <token>
            <description>
                The D4Science Service Authorization Token. The user has to do a subscription to get it
            </description>
            <value>
                528fb642-187a-4bdc-8b4d-2ca8cf98b62d
            </value>
        </token>
        <language>
            <description>
                Tag used to specify in which language have been written the documents to annotate
            </description>
            <value>
                en
            </value>
        </language>
        <epsilon>
            <description>
                This parameter can be used to finely tune the disambiguation process. You browse the site
                https://sobigdata.d4science.org/web/tagme/tagme-help to get more information
            </description>
            <value>
                0.3
            </value>
        </epsilon>
        <include_wikicategory>
            <description>
                Tag used to include within the response the categories list of the wikipedia pages.
            </description>
            <value>
                true
            </value>
        </include_wikicategory>
    </tagme_info>

    <pubmed_parameters>
        <url4pmids>
            <description>
                The url used to download a list of new pmid insert in the pubmed database
            </description>
            <value>
                https://eutils.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/eutils/esearch.fcgi
            </value>
        </url4pmids>
        <retmax>
            <description>
                This is a parameter used to get the max number of pmids per query. I suggest you to increase the value
                only if your driver machine has more then 8 GB of RAM. You have to know that if this value is high then
                your driver will download many titles and abstract per query. So, it could cause an out of memory state.
            </description>
            <value>
                5000
            </value>
        </retmax>
        <retstart>
            <description>
                This is a parameter used to specify from which index of the vector will be start the download function
            </description>
            <value>
                0
            </value>
        </retstart>
        <url4abstract>
            <description>
                The url used to download the title and abstract of the new articles
            </description>
            <value>
                https://eutils.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/eutils/efetch.fcgi
            </value>
        </url4abstract>
        <end_update_date>
            <description>
                Upper bound of the date range used to limit a search result by the date. The general
                date format is YYYY/MM/DD, YYYY/MM or YYYY. If this field is set to 3000, it will specify
                the today data.
            </description>
            <value>
                2020/04/30
            </value>
        </end_update_date>
    </pubmed_parameters>

    <dt_hybrid_parameters>
        <alpha>
            <description>
                The wid1 and wid2 degree will be raised to this value
            </description>
            <value>
                0.5
            </value>
        </alpha>
        <top>
            <description>
                We only consider the top n associations for each wid1. The default value is 1000
            </description>
            <value>
                500
            </value>
        </top>
    </dt_hybrid_parameters>

    <hdfs_paths>
        <!-- path used during the updating operations -->
        <newDocuments_path>
            <descrizione>
                The hdfs path in which are stored all the json files containing the new documents' abstract and title to
                annotate
            </descrizione>
            <value>
                /Articles_update
            </value>
        </newDocuments_path>
        <!-- path used during the annotation of the whole documents dataset -->
        <allDocuments_path>
            <description>
                The hdfs path in which are stored the json file containing all the Pubmed documents' title and abstract
                until june 2017
            </description>
            <value>
                /Article_jsonFormat
            </value>
        </allDocuments_path>
        <!-- -->
        <DocumentsAnnotations_path>
            <description>
                The hdfs path in which are stored the annotations related to the new documents downloaded from Pubmed
            </description>
            <value>
                /Documents_Annotations
            </value>
        </DocumentsAnnotations_path>
        <!-- -->
        <categories_path>
            <description>
                The hdfs path in which are stored the parquet files containing all wikipedia biology categories.
            </description>
            <value>
                /categories_biotgm
            </value>
        </categories_path>
        <!-- -->
        <pmids_wiki_ids_path>
            <description>
                The hdfs path in which are stored the association pmid-wid
            </description>
            <value>
                /pmids_wiki_ids_path
            </value>
        </pmids_wiki_ids_path>
        <!-- -->
        <wiki_ids_spot_path>
            <description>
                The hdfs path in which are stored the association wid-spot
            </description>
            <value>
                /wiki_ids_spot_path
            </value>
        </wiki_ids_spot_path>
        <!-- -->
        <w_matrix_path>
            <description>
                The hdfs path in which is stored the w_matrix (DT-Hybrid)
            </description>
            <value>
                /w_matrix_path
            </value>
        </w_matrix_path>
        <!-- -->
        <wid1_wid2_path>
            <description>
                The hdfs path in which are stored the parquet files containing the widi-widj association. where widi and
                widj are two wiki id of two different terms obtained during the annotation procedures
            </description>
            <value>
                /widi_widj_association
            </value>
        </wid1_wid2_path>
        <!-- -->
        <tagme_relatedness>
            <description>
                The hdfs path in which is stored the relatedness between two wiki ids
            </description>
            <value>
                /tagme_relatedness
            </value>
        </tagme_relatedness>
        <!-- DISEASE PATHS -->
        <disgenet_path>
            <description>
                The hdfs path in which is stored the disgenet tsv file containing diseases information
            </description>
            <value>
                /DISEASE/DISGENET
            </value>
        </disgenet_path>
        <kegg_dis_path>
            <description>
                The hdfs path in which is stored the kegg csv file containing diseases information
            </description>
            <value>
                /DISEASE/KEGG
            </value>
        </kegg_dis_path>
        <civic_dis_path>
            <description>
                The hdfs path in which is stored the civic json file containing diseases information
            </description>
            <value>
                /DISEASE/CIVIC
            </value>
        </civic_dis_path>
        <!-- DRUG PATHS-->
        <drugbank_path>
            <description>
                The hdfs path in which is stored the drugbanck csv file containing drugs information
            </description>
            <value>
                /DRUG/DRUGBANCK
            </value>
        </drugbank_path>
        <kegg_drg_path>
            <description>
                The hdfs path in which is stored the kegg csv file containing drugs information
            </description>
            <value>
                /DRUG/KEGG
            </value>
        </kegg_drg_path>
        <pharmkb_path>
            <description>
                The hdfs path in which is stored the pharmkb csv file containing drugs information
            </description>
            <value>
                /DRUG/PHARMKB
            </value>
        </pharmkb_path>
        <!-- GENE PATHS -->
        <hgnc_path>
            <description>
                The hdfs path in which is stored the hgnc txt file containing genes information
            </description>
            <value>
                /GENE/HGNC
            </value>
        </hgnc_path>
        <!-- miRNA PATHS -->
        <mirna_path>
            <description>
                The hdfs path in which is stored the mirna txt file containing miRNA information
            </description>
            <value>
                /miRNA/miRNA
            </value>
        </mirna_path>
        <mirna_mat_path>
            <description>
                The hdfs path in which is stored the mirna_mature txt file containing miRNA information
            </description>
            <value>
                /miRNA/miRNA_MATURE
            </value>
        </mirna_mat_path>
        <!-- PROTEIN -->
        <string_path>
            <description>
                The hdfs path in which is stored the aliases, names of the protein as well as the file containing the whole string network
            </description>
            <value>
                /PROTEIN/STRING
            </value>
        </string_path>
        <string_species>
            <description>

            </description>
            <value>
                9606
            </value>
        </string_species>
        <!-- GO -->
        <go_path>
            <description>
                The hdfs path in which is stored the go obo file containing ontology information
            </description>
            <value>
                /ONTOLOGY/GO
            </value>
        </go_path>
        <!-- ENZYME -->
        <enzyme_path>
            <description>
                The hdfs path in which is stored the csv file containing enzyme information
            </description>
            <value>
                /ENZYME/KEGG
            </value>
        </enzyme_path>
        <!-- DGROUP -->
        <dgroup_path>
            <description>
                The hdfs path in which is stored the csv file containing dgroup information
            </description>
            <value>
                /DGROUP/KEGG
            </value>
        </dgroup_path>
        <!-- LNC -->
        <lnc_path>
            <description>
                The hdfs path in which is stored the csv file containing lnc information
            </description>
            <value>
                /LNC/LNCIPEDIA
            </value>
        </lnc_path>
        <!-- NETWORKS DATA -->
        <network_data>
            <description>
                The hdfs path in which will be stored the network data
            </description>
            <value>
                /NETWORK_DATA
            </value>
        </network_data>
    </hdfs_paths>


</configuration>